Nissa Elchhab . Jarvis Consulting

I am a Junior Software Developer, with experience in Java, React, Golang and Ruby on Rails. I graduated from Open-Classrooms with a E.U bachelor equivalent. I am passionate about software quality and well-engineered solutions that take into account green or efficient tech, and social responsibility. I was, previously, a member of the Tier 3 Network Assurance and Provisioning Team at Telus, as a Telecom Network Technician. Besides that, I hold a diploma as a Telecom/electronics Technologist and a Bachelor in Business Administration with a Marketing major. I believe that lean, secure, and Open Source software can bring a unique added value to all the stakeholders, and clearer communication and can enable optimized and agile solutions to market needs. My other interests are Information Security and science education.

Skills

Proficient: Java, Maven, Linux/Bash, RDBMS/PostgreSQL, Agile/Scrum, Git, Github, Javascript (ES6), Golang, Ruby on Rails

Competent: Spring Boot, Docker, Postman (API testing and design), HTML5/CSS3, REST API, Testing using JUnit and related libraries

Familiar: C/C++, OWASP / Kali Linux / Wireshark, UML / ERD, Cloud services (Google Cloud, Microsoft Azure), SSL/TLS/OAuth, Virtualization (Linux KVM, VMware ESXi)

Jarvis Projects

Project source code: https://github.com/jarviscanada/jarvis_data_eng_NissaElchhab

Cluster Monitor [GitHub]: Not Started

Core Java Apps [GitHub]:

- Twitter App: .
- JDBC App: .
- Grep App: .

Highlighted Projects

Build a geolocalized aid platform for your neighborhood: Backend in Ruby on Rails API mode, running on Azure VM with ngnix and HTTPS/TLS; Frontend in React/Javascript/leafletjs [GitHub]: For the Bakdend and API, I designed, developed tested, and cloud-hosted an API that looks for nearby volunteer services or offers of help and serves that data to an authenticated frontend using HTTPS. As for the frontend (https://github.com/RtillaWork/P_8_FE), it was built in React and LeafletJs, as a map, that communicates with the API to link users' needing help with volunteers in the vicinity.

Build a webscraper and dowloader of online library catalogs and open public library resources [GitHub]: Built a webscraper of public library resources, particularily ArchiveGrid and OCLC with Go and Gocolly to facilitate exploratory research, downloading references and eventually as a simpler command line search engine. Created a C++ utility to clean and extract preliminary data.

Professional Experiences

Software Developer, Jarvis (2022-present): Worked under the mentorship of a Senior developer and a Scrum Master to translate user stories to readable and maintanable Java code to perform the required tasks. Wrote unit and integration tests to document and assert application correctness. Refered to documentation to tacle edge cases and collaborated with other teammates to share useful documentation and tutorials.

Self-employed, Software Developer (Go, C++), Self-employed (2022): Worked with a client, a phD student, to research, design and create a webscrapping application in Golang that helped accelerate the client research by specific keywords and using a simple CLI interface to launch and download relevant research documents from online public library catalogues

Telecommunications Network Technician, Tier 3 Service Delivery and Assurance, TELUS Communications (2009-2019): Tier 3 Service Delivery and Assurance for POTS and Fibre voice and data services. Performed Service

Delivery and Assurance related to trouble analysis and resolution; documented and provisioned services (triple-play) on copper, fibre, SS7, SIP, and Long Distance), Collaborated with the Voice Test Team, QA, other departments and other International carriers to solve complex Trouble Tickets.

Junior Computer Network Technician, Adil Réseaux (Morocco) (2003-2005): Assist researching cost-effective solutions for, and setting up Microsoft networks for SOHO, Assist in securing LANs using Windows' Group Policies in an AD setup, Translate relevant documentation from English to French for local customers, Assist in training users in Microsoft products, basic Redhat Linux, Mac OS X, and basic internet applications

Education

OpenClassrooms (2018-2021), Diploma, Level 6 qualification on the European Qualification Framework, Software Developer - Full Stack (Développeur · se d'application) - Cursus includes 9 real-world projects

NAIT (Northern Alberta Institute of Technology) (2007-2009), Honour Diploma Telecommunications Engineering Technology, School of Applied Sciences and Technology, Telecommunications and Electronics Engineering Technology - Dean's Honour Roll

Groupe ISCAE (1999-2003), Bachelor in Business Administration, Marketing major, School of Management (Casablanca)

Miscellaneous

- Google IT support, Coursera (2020)
- How to use OpenVAS for vulnerability assessment, Cybrary (2020)
- Splunk basics, RangeForce (2020)
- Cisco Certified Network Associate, Cisco (2013)
- French: Native proficiency
- English: Bilingual proficiency
- Arabic: Professional proficiency
- Learning Morse and preparing for a Ham(Amateur Radio) certification
- Exploring embedded hardware such as Raspberry Pi and BBC Micro::Bit